{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "One leader of this state, John McKinly, was captured in bed by the British. The Swedish settlement of Fort Christina is located in this state. This state disputed a small tract known as the Wedge with its northern neighbor until 1921. Until it gained an independent legislature in 1701, it was known as the “Three Lower Counties.” This state’s northern border is an arc centered on the courthouse in New Castle, the Twelve-Mile Circle, and its western border is the Mason-Dixon line. For ten points, name this small Mid-Atlantic state where an 1861 vote against secession from the Union was taken in Dover.",
      "answer": "Delaware"
    },
    {
      "question": "A videotape showing this man with Thomas Youk ends with this man challenging the authorities to convict him. Shortly after this man worked with Janet Adkins, the state of Michigan revoked his license. This man employed the use of the Mercitron and the Thanatron to deliver, respectively, carbon monoxide or an IV drip of lethal medicine. For ten points, name this doctor who, in 1999, was convicted of murder and served eight years in prison for his role in over one hundred physician-assisted suicides.",
      "answer": "Dr. Jack Kevorkian"
    },
    {
      "question": "This composer wrote the piece “A new song we raise” in response to the execution of Johann Esch and Heinrich Voes. J.S. Bach wrote a set of canonic variations on his Christmas piece “Vom himmel hoch.” Another of his hymns was quoted in the finale of Felix Mendelssohn’s fifth symphony, written for the 300th anniversary of the Augsburg Confession. “A Mighty Fortress is Our God” was written by, for ten points, what German whose hymns and other religious writings, including the Ninety-Five Theses, helped initiate the Protestant Reformation?",
      "answer": "Martin Luther"
    },
    {
      "question": "This organization defended its unorthodox contractual procedure in a court case against Iain Fraser. It is currently lead by Don Garber and unofficially runs the Cascadia Cup. Its first ever match was contested between San Jose Clash and DCU at Spartan Stadium, and it grew out of the failed NASL. This league’s Designated Player rule has allowed David Villa, Kaka, and other imports to join it, as its attractiveness to foreigners grew following David Beckham’s transfer to the LA Galaxy. For ten points, name this modern American soccer league.",
      "answer": "Major League Soccer or MLS"
    },
    {
      "question": "As part of this policy, Raycom Sports planned a football game between USC and Illinois in Dynamo Stadium. This policy led to the success of the Phosphorite War. The anti-Stalinist novel Children of the Arbat was allowed to be published under this system. Along with a policy translated as “restructuring,” this policy helped lead to the independence of many constituent republics of the Eastern Bloc. For ten points, name this policy under Mikhail Gorbachev that advocated for greater freedom of speech and government transparency and comes from the Russian word for “openness.”",
      "answer": "glasnost"
    },
    {
      "question": "This commander argued for the release of German soldiers in World War II, noting that he had given orders similar to the ones the Germans were in prison for. This victor at the battle of Wonju was noted for his defensive use of artillery against human wave attacks, granting his strategy the nickname of “meatgrinder.” This commander of the Eighth Army assumed his highest post at the Wake Island Conference after Harry Truman had removed his predecessor. For ten points, name this successor of Douglas MacArthur in the Korean War.",
      "answer": "Matthew Ridgway"
    },
    {
      "question": "The day before 2004 elections on this island, Annette Lu and Chen Shui-bian were shot. After easier negotiations for part of Liaodong and the Penghu Islands, China begrudgingly granted Japan control of this island in the 1895 Treaty of Shimonoseki. Lee Teng-hui once served as president of a government that rules this island, where Tsai Ing-wen was elected president in 2016.. For ten points, name this island, formerly known as Formosa, that, since 1949, has been home to the government of the People’s Republic of China.",
      "answer": [
        "Taiwan",
        "Formosa before mentioned"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "A Polish World War II refugee is hired by the McIntyre family in this author’s “The Displaced Person.” One of this author’s characters forms the “Holy Church of Christ Without Christ” to rival the street preaching of atheist World War II veteran Hazel Motes. In another of this author’s stories, Julian resents his racist mother, yet accompanies her on the bus to the Y. For ten points, name this Southern Gothic author of Wise Blood and the collection Everything that Rises Must Converge and A Good Man is Hard to Find.",
      "answer": "Flannery O’Connor"
    },
    {
      "question": "Nell Gwynn was one of many women to have had affairs with this man, who hid in an oak tree near Boscobel House to avoid capture after the Battle of Worcester. During this man’s rule, non-allied ministers were banned from coming within five miles of their former parishes as part of the Clarendon Code, passed by the Cavalier Parliament. The Great Fire of London struck during the reign of, for ten points, what restored Stuart monarch whose father was beheaded during the English Civil War?",
      "answer": "Charles II"
    },
    {
      "question": "Due to his cruelty, this man was replaced by Francisco de Bobadilla in a position that he had been granted by the Capitulations of Santa Fe. This man outlined what he was owed by the Spanish Crown in the Book of Privileges. This man forced the Taino to pay him tribute after colonizing their home, which was later named Hispaniola. For ten points, name this Italian explorer whose voyages, funded by Ferdinand and Isabella, led to Spanish colonization in the New World.",
      "answer": "Christopher Columbus or Cristobal Colon"
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The loser of this battle made the mistake of deploying Richard Caswell’s militia against his enemy’s strongest flank. It was preceded by the battle of Waxhaws. Johann de Kalb was killed during this battle, which was prompted by Lord Rawdon’s calls for aid. This battle was decided when the North Carolina and Delaware regiments were broken by Tarleton’s Legion. This victory for Charles Cornwallis led colonial leadership to appoint Nathanael Greene as commander in the South. For ten points, name this British victory in the Carolinas that destroyed the reputation of Horatio Gates.",
        "answer": "Battle of Camden"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The Carolina campaign had been turned over to Cornwallis following this commander’s withdrawal. This commander had earlier led the disastrous attempt at taking Charleston.",
        "answer": "Sir Henry Clinton"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Two answers required. Captain Polin led a diplomatic mission headed by the flagship Reale from one of these countries to the other. In a joint operation, these two countries successfully besieged the city of Nice during the Italian War of 1542-46. Thousands of soldiers of the losing side were executed in the aftermath of the 1799 Siege of Jaffa between these two countries. For ten points, name these two countries that formed an “unholy alliance” based on their mutual hatred of the Habsburgs and were led by Francis I and Suleiman the Magnificent.",
        "answer": [
          "France and the Ottoman Empire",
          "Valois dynasty for France"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "One of the most valuable resources the Ottoman Empire had to offer France was what admiral, who smashed the Habsburg fleet at the Battle of Preveza?",
        "answer": "Hayreddin Barbarossa"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This thinker wrote that “our aversions and judgments are not, by any means, primarily rational in character” in reference to attitudes to superficial features, like face shape and race. This figure studied how a tribe seemed to shift from patrilineal to matrilineal society; that Vancouver-area tribe was the Kwakiutl. This scholar’s “four field” approach included linguistic and archaeological research and was taught to students like Alfred Kroeber, Ruth Benedict, and Margaret Mead. For ten points, name this American thinker, the founder of Columbia University’s revolutionary anthropology school and author of The Mind of Primitive Man.",
        "answer": "Franz Boas"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This Kwakiutl gift-giving ceremony, common to many Native American tribes in the Pacific Northwest, was studied by Boaz. This practice was once banned as a “useless custom” by federal officials.",
        "answer": "potlatch"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "As head of this institution, James Johnston was assaulted by Burton Phillips. William Miller and Harold Stites were killed during the “Battle of [this location],” which resulted in the execution of Miran Thompson and Sam Shockley. Edward Wutke committed suicide using a pencil sharpener while at this location. Frank Morris and the Anglin brothers briefly lived at this location, where Robert Stroud was sent in his transfer from Leavenworth. Al Capone briefly lived in, for ten points, what supposedly unescapable island prison located in San Francisco Bay?",
        "answer": [
          "Alcatraz Federal Penitentiary",
          "Alcatraz Island"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The aforementioned Robert Stroud earned this nickname, inspired by one of his hobbies.",
        "answer": "Birdman"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "William Wade Dudley was accused of bribing electoral voters into selecting this man in the Blocks of Five Scandal. This President dealt with the crisis caused by the killing of two sailors from the USS Baltimore. Levi Morton served as Vice President under this man, who signed the McKinley Tariff and Sherman Antitrust Act. The 51st Congress, nicknamed the Billion Dollar Congress, served alongside, for ten points, what U.S. President who was succeeded and preceded in office by Grover Cleveland?",
        "answer": "Benjamin Harrison"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This Chinese general was sent to Korea during the Donghak Peasant Rebellion. Following the Xinhai [shin-hai] revolution, this general tried to proclaim himself the Hongxian emperor.",
        "answer": "Yuan Shikai"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This work was appended by the essay “General Scholium,” in which its author claimed that he did not pretend to know things he didn’t know, a concept now called hypotheses non fingo. This work drew extensively on the observations of John Flamsteed, which was used to study Kepler’s laws. The three-body problem was explored in this work, which attempts to explain the motion of the Moon under the gravity of the Earth and the Sun. Its insights include a law that states that force equals mass times acceleration. For ten points, name this work that states the law of gravitation and the laws of motion, written by Isaac Newton.",
        "answer": "Philosophiae Naturalis Principia Mathematica"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Newton was accused of stealing ideas from what physicist, who, as a biologist, also coined the word “cell”?",
        "answer": "Robert Hooke"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This monarch dealt with the alliance of Hugh X and Henry III at the battle of Taillebourg. The Talmud was burned under the reign of this monarch, who fought in Tunis alongside Edward Longshanks of England. This monarch died of dysentery while attempting to reverse the outcome of the battle of Al Mansurah, which was preceded by his capture of Damietta. This participant in the Seventh and Eighth crusades collected many relics for the Sainte Chapelle chapel, and he was known for his devotion to Catholicism. For ten points, name this canonized monarch of France.",
        "answer": "Saint Louis or Louis IX"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Louis the Saint fought with these slave soldiers, whose ranks included Baibars and Qutuz. They would grow to control Egypt and repulse a Mongol invasion at Ain Jalut.",
        "answer": "Mamluks"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "One of these events, known as qatl-e-aam, started when a leader rode into the Chandi Chowk market and unsheathed his sword. Another of these events was preceded by a battle in which flaming camels were used to combat war elephants and resulted in a pyramid made of 80,000 human skulls. Nadir Shah led one of these events, which was preceded by the Battle of Karnal, and that one of these events caused the capture of the Kooh-i-Noor diamond and the Peacock Throne. For ten points, name these events in which an invading force looted the final Mughal capital.",
        "answer": [
          "sacks of Delhi or sacks of Shahjahanabad",
          "equivalents for sack"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Yet another, later sack of Delhi occurred due to the invasion of Ahmad Shah Durrani, who later won the Third Battle of Panipat against what empire founded by Shivaji?",
        "answer": [
          "Maratha Empire",
          "Maratha Confederacy"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The 10th century Denkard compendium lists customs of this religion. Invocations to Apas and Zam, or water and earth, are collected in this religion’s Vendidad. This religion holds that the forces of asha and druj work against each other and that souls must cross the Chinvat Bridge for judgment. The legendary king Vishtaspa was the first adherent of this religion, whose worshipers gather in fire temples. The Avesta is the holy scripture of, for ten points, what Iranian religion whose Avesta collects the Gathas, the sayings of its founder, Zarathustra?",
        "answer": "Zoroastrianism"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "In Zoroastrianism, Ahura Mazda is opposed by this representation of chaos and the destructive spirit. His name is often written upside down in texts to indicate disapproval.",
        "answer": "Ahriman or Angra Mainyu"
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "EARLY FLORIDA",
      "prompt": "In the history of Florida, who or what was the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "European kingdom that first explored and settled Florida?",
          "answer": "Kingdom of Spain"
        },
        {
          "question": "explorer from that country who legendarily discovered Florida looking for the Fountain of Youth?",
          "answer": "Juan Ponce de Le´on"
        },
        {
          "question": "first permanent European settlement in Florida from 1565?",
          "answer": "St. Augustine or San Augustin"
        },
        {
          "question": "founder of Georgia who led a 1740 siege of that settlement?",
          "answer": "James Oglethorpe"
        },
        {
          "question": "longest river of Florida on which the French established Fort Caroline?",
          "answer": "St. Johns River"
        },
        {
          "question": "explorer who arrived in Florida before becoming the first European to cross the Mississippi River?",
          "answer": "Hernando de Soto"
        },
        {
          "question": "treaty which ceded Florida to the United States?",
          "answer": "Adams-On´ıs Treaty"
        },
        {
          "question": "earlier treaty which had established the southern border of the U.S. along the Florida-Georgia line?",
          "answer": [
            "Pinckney’s Treaty",
            "the Treaty of San Lorenzo ELIZABETH II"
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "From the life of Elizabeth II, identify...",
      "prompt": "Name the from the life of elizabeth ii, identify......",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "the London residence where she awoke one morning to find Michael Fagan in her room.",
          "answer": [
            "Buckingham Palace",
            "Buckingham House"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "the country where she was targeted by the Lithgow Plot while in South New Wales.",
          "answer": "Australia"
        },
        {
          "question": "the Berkshire Castle where she spent most of World War II.",
          "answer": "Windsor Castle"
        },
        {
          "question": "her father who ascended to the throne in 1937.",
          "answer": "George VI"
        },
        {
          "question": "the type of jubilee she celebrated in 2012.",
          "answer": "Diamond Jubilee"
        },
        {
          "question": "her uncle who abdicated the throne in 1936.",
          "answer": "Edward VIII"
        },
        {
          "question": "the name she used to refer to 1992 due to its challenges.",
          "answer": [
            "annus horribilis",
            "horrible year"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "the 17 year-old who shot six blanks at her in 1981.",
          "answer": "Marcus Simon Sarjeant"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "MOROCCO",
      "prompt": "In the history of Morocco, what is the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "oft-sieged peninsula at the south of Iberia separated from Morocco by a namesake strait?",
          "answer": "Gibraltar"
        },
        {
          "question": "largest city of Morocco, once called Anfa, given its current name during a period of Spanish rule?",
          "answer": "Casablanca"
        },
        {
          "question": "second-largest Moroccan city and home to the world’s longest-running university, Al Quaraouiyine?",
          "answer": "Fez"
        },
        {
          "question": "southern territory over which Morocco won sovereignty in a 1975 to 1991 conflict?",
          "answer": "Western Sahara"
        },
        {
          "question": "north African ethnic group that ruled Morocco from the 11th century?",
          "answer": "Berber or Amazigh"
        },
        {
          "question": "dynasty of that ethnic group that led Morocco until its defeat by the Almohads?",
          "answer": "Almoravid dynasty"
        },
        {
          "question": "war Spain fought against members of that ethnic group in a namesake mountainous region?",
          "answer": "Rif War"
        },
        {
          "question": "King of Morocco from 1961 to 1999 and namesake of the country’s largest mosque?",
          "answer": "Hassan II"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The first member of this group forbade gold and silver statues to be made of him; that man’s authority diminished when Casparius Aelianus demanded that he hand over the murderers of his predecessor. Edward Gibbon stated that this group’s rule was “the most (20 pts)",
        "happy and prosperous” period in world history. This group’s name was coined by Niccolo Machiavelli, who suggested that this group was successful because they were all (10 pts)",
        "adopted and did not inherit their position. For ten points, name this group of Roman rulers whose rule from 96 to 180 CE was marked by peace and prosperity."
      ],
      "answer": "Five Good Emperors"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This leader planned Operation Lal Dora, which was a proposed invasion of Mauritius. This leader’s passing of the 26th amendment led to the abolition of the Privy Purse. One slogan used by this leader called to “garib hatao,” or “abolish poverty.” The (20 pts)",
        "Allahabad High Court declared this leader’s election null and void due to malpractice, which led to a period of rule by decree known as The (10 pts)",
        "Emergency. After ordering Operation Blue Star, this leader was assassinated by her Sikh Bodyguards. For ten points, name this daughter of Jawaharlal Nehru who served as Prime Minister of India."
      ],
      "answer": "Indira Gandhi"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) A member of the “neo-” school of this thinker’s views, Paul R. Ehrlich, wrote about rising death rates and the self-sufficiency of India in a 1968 book titled for a certain quantity’s (20 pts)",
        "“bomb.” This man argued that a certain payment system could be a form of surplus in The Nature of Rent. This economist contrasted the (10 pts)",
        "arithmetic growth of the food supply with the geometric growth of the human population in his most famous work. For ten points, name this English economist whose An Essay on the Principle of Population predicted widespread starvation."
      ],
      "answer": "Thomas Robert Malthus"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This man did not personally go on a voyage he organized that installed Mana Vikraman as king of Calicut. This man’s political interventions included capturing the usurper (20 pts)",
        "Sekandar of Semudera and capturing King Alagonakkara of Kotte. On his first voyage, this man captured the pirate Chen Zuyi. On his fifth voyage, this man explored the (10 pts)",
        "Arabian coast from Hormuz to Aden before sailing as far south as Mombasa and bringing a giraffe to the Yongle Emperor. For ten points, name this admiral who organized seven voyages for the Ming Dynasty."
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Zheng He",
        "Ma Sanbao",
        "Ma He"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) George Pearkes described a contingency for this action as a “fantastic desperate plan” which “just might have worked.” That plan, developed by James Brown, called for the immediate seizure of the Great Falls at the occurrence of this event. (20 pts)",
        "Defense Scheme No. 1 was designed to prevent this action which was called for in War Plan Crimson. In planning for this action, one government noted that Route 99 “is the best practicable route to (10 pts)",
        "Vancouver.” For ten points, name this hypothetical action in which American forces would have attempted to seize cities like Ottawa."
      ],
      "answer": "U.S. invasion of Canada"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This city was defended by the impromptu Team SNAFU. The last tanks around this city were organized around William Desobry, Henry Cherry, and James O Hara. The 5th Army of Hasso von Manteuffel attempted to capture (20 pts)",
        "St. Vith and this city, which one commander promised to relieve in 48 hours. This city was besieged by German forces attempting to reach (10 pts)",
        "Antwerp, but was relieved by Patton’s 3rd Army. For ten points, name this Belgian city whose siege during the Battle of the Bulge prompted Anthony McAuliffe’s famous surrender reply, “Nuts.”"
      ],
      "answer": "Siege of Bastogne"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) In March 2016, this organization noted that “Tariq Ramadan is never going to grab a Kalashnikov” in an editorial that laments the retreat of secularism. That editorial blamed bakers who refuse to sell ham for their role in the (20 pts)",
        "Brussels attacks, which this organization called “the visible part of a very large iceberg.” G´erard Biard [bee-arhd] is the (10 pts)",
        "editor-in-chief of this organization, for which Jean Cabut [zhan ka-boo] and St´ephane Charbonnier [steff-ahn sharb-ohn-ee-ay] worked as cartoonists until a January 2015 attack. The editorial “How did we end up here?” was published by, for ten points, what satirical French newspaper?"
      ],
      "answer": "Charlie Hebdo"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) A political cartoon made in response to this speech shows a red-caped anarchy behind a man wielding stolen regalia. Its speaker noted that “We come to speak for this broader class of businessman” as “the individual is but an (20 pts)",
        "atom,” and cried “We beg no longer, we entreat no more...We defy them!” This speech advocated a platform that included a (10 pts)",
        "16-to-1 exchange ratio, comparing the status quo to a “crown of thorns”. For ten points, name this speech that sealed the 1896 Democratic nomination for William Jennings Bryan, who demanded that mankind not be “crucified” on the title object."
      ],
      "answer": "Cross of Gold speech"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This group largely took inspiration from Carlos Marighella’s Minimanual of the Urban Guerilla. Members of this group committed suicide during “death night” while being held in Stammheim Prison. The first incarnation of this group is referred to as the (20 pts)",
        "Baader-Meinhof Gang, and it was responsible for the deaths of Jurgen Ponto and Hanns Schleyer during the (10 pts)",
        "1977 German Autumn. For ten points, name this West German left-wing terrorist group that operated during the 1970s."
      ],
      "answer": "Red Army Faction"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) One of these people appears in an 1888 painting depicting his purported smothering of party guests with rose petals dropped from the ceiling. A boy’s face is scratched out of a well-preserved tondo depicting one of these people with his wife and two sons. A baby riding on a (20 pts)",
        "dolphin grabs onto the cloak of one of these people in a statue discovered in the city of Prima Porta. A gilt bronze statue of one of these people stands atop a (10 pts)",
        "column with a spiral bas-relief depicting his victory in the Dacian War. For ten points, name these people depicted in works like The Roses of Heliogabalus and on Trajan’s Column."
      ],
      "answer": "Emperors of Rome or Caesar"
    }
  ]
}